Robert Johnson

LEAD SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Phone: 417-522-5796 | Email: robjkc@gmail.com | Springfield, MO

SUMMARY

I am a customer-centric Software Engineer with a history of architecting and building multiple large-scale systems. My mission is to create intuitive user experiences that bring delight to the end user and enable them to work more efficiently.

SKILLS

Languages- Go, Java, C#, C++, TypeScript

Technologies – React, Angular, Nx, HTML, CSS, Java Swing, JavaFX, UI/UX, Single-SPA, Agile Project Management, Jira, Confluence, PostgreSQL, MySQL, MSSQL, RabbitMQ, Oracle, REST APIs, Git

Cloud - Kubernetes (k8s), Telepresence, Rancher, AWS, Tilt, Docker, Kustomize

EXPERIENCE

Lead Software Engineer at Digital Monitoring Products | Springfield, MO | Feb 2020 - Present

- Lead Engineer developing video-based security applications utilizing Go, React, and GraphQL.
- Led several initiatives including implementation of a CI/CD workflow, API Gateway, and Kubernetes developer platform.

Senior Software Engineer at O'Reilly Auto Parts | Springfield, MO | Oct 2003 – Feb 2020

- Lead architect and developer for Java graphical point-of-sale application deployed to over 4,000 stores.
- Creation of an advanced catalog system used for search and display of millions of automotive parts.

Independent iPhone Developer at RetainIt | Springfield, MO | Oct 2013 – Jan 2016

• Designed and developed a successful iPhone application, RetainIt - Organize & Todo, featured several times in the top 100 productivity apps.

President/Lead Developer at Playfantasy.com | Springfield, MO | Nov 2001 – Jan 2004

• Design and development of a multi-user fantasy football website.

Senior Software Engineer at Sprint Corp | Kansas City, MO | Jan 2000 – Nov 2001

• Design and development of distributed telecommunication applications.

EDUCATION

Computer Science, BS - Missouri State University | Springfield, MO

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/robert-johnson-69a1869

https://github.com/robikc